<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Properties of a cat</title>
    <description>balaji damodaran&#39;s blog about programming and life</description>
    <link>http://balaji-damodaran.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://balaji-damodaran.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2015 03:03:59 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2015 03:03:59 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Javadhu Hills - II</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So, its been a long time since I went for a ride (more than 50 days) and I was busy with office work, but finally there was a window of opportunity to sieze and did I sieze or not!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to Javadhu hills, I’ve already been to Jamunamarathur, but this time I wanted to go beyond that and reach Vellore on the other side, and this is how it went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was so excited the previous day itself, during such days I don’t have to keep an alarm. I woke up by 5, but there were 2 reasons why I left by 7. One, my phone was switched off due to excess youtube watching by Roja and I had to clean my bowel. FYI, I do not have an excellent healthy body and my internals are pretty messed up. I’ll cut the story short and say that by 7 both my targets were achieved and I was on my way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a coffee and some sandwiches to start with so I decided to skip ‘regular’ breakfast. As usual, the porur-ponamallee road is broken beyond redemption due to a lot of hardware industries that needs heavy trucks for transport and very little common sense. So it took a lot of time for me to reach the first checkpoint - Sri Motel Highway. From there onwards there was no stopping, I rode on. My bladder was full due to some of the experiements to clean my bowel and I had to stop once or twice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the infamous vibrations (I’m never going to buy another Royal Enfield product again until I hear “there are No vibrations!” in the review), the sidebox for the air filter just ‘opened’ with the lock on (A bit more on this: I always find the sidebox slammed shut so tight to the point that you can’t even open it, now I know the reason) because the lock unscrewed itself due to vibrations. I heard noises and I had to slam shut the sidebox after screwing on the lock nut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/to-jamunamarathur.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;On the way to Jamunamarathur&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 class=&quot;center&quot; id=&quot;on-the-way-to-jamunamarathur&quot;&gt;On the way to Jamunamarathur&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stopped on the second toll, bought some cigarettes and continued on - Arcot, Arani, Polur, Jamunamarathur. Then I took a right en route to Amirthi. To road to Jamunamarathur is fun, its a hill road with some twisties and sceneries, I stopped for some pictures, but the real deal was the Amirthi road - it starts with a lot of S bends, one such was a bit steep and I locked my gears and fell at 5 kmph, since it was almost a stationary fall no damage was done. Once the S bends were over, the road climbs down and I had a spectacular view of the hills but a bit scary as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/to-amirthi.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;On the way to Amirthi&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 class=&quot;center&quot; id=&quot;on-the-way-to-amirthi&quot;&gt;On the way to Amirthi&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what google maps tells you - that there is no road between Amirthi and Vellore. It is in a way true - there is a stream that crosses this road and it washed away the road, but the good part is that the road is still crossable because for most of the year because the stream is dry. But since there *was* a stream and that there is *no* road, the path is soft and hollow. There must’ve been some rain in the previous days and it has made a ditch in that part. I was unsure whether I can cross the muddy ditch without sinking my shoes in it, but thankfully my shoes were safe and I managed to cross it in one go. This was eventful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/amirthi.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Amirthi to Vellore on Google maps&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 class=&quot;center&quot; id=&quot;amirthi-to-vellore-on-google-maps&quot;&gt;Amirthi to Vellore on Google maps&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I reached Vellore, had biriyani and reached home in one stretch without stopping, the time when I reached home was 4.30ish and it was worth every kilometer. I slept immediately and woke up only by 8 for dinner and now I’m writing this post at night 2.40 AM. Here’s to more such rides in the future!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2015 06:41:54 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://balaji-damodaran.com/personal/2015/10/11/javadhu-hills.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://balaji-damodaran.com/personal/2015/10/11/javadhu-hills.html</guid>
        
        <category>motorcycling</category>
        
        <category>Javadhu hills</category>
        
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Monopoly for a 4.5 year old</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I loved board games, back in my days I never had the exposure, knowledge and financial support to explore more complex games - snake &amp;amp; ladder and monopoly (called business game in my region) are the only games I remember.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a 4.5 year old daughter. She lives up to the stereotype that girls are more mature than boys in comparison. I’m waiting for her to get a bit more older so that we can play board games together. I have a few games in mind such as Settlers of Catan, D&amp;amp;D, Chess. But I feel she is old enough to play Monopoly. I think it is a great way to introduce the concept of money, investment and financial risk management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other skills I want to introduce to my kids are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reading-books&quot;&gt;reading books.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She is less than 5 years old and can’t comprehend english properly, so I need to wait for a few more years, but for now, I should read it to her in her mother tongue at least - Tamil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;learn-fine-arts-and-performing-arts&quot;&gt;learn fine arts and performing arts.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One or two dance forms, one or two musical instruments, painting/drawing/coloring or maybe something else that she is interested in. I’m not going to force her on this one, but usually, humans + art is natural. You don’t need to force a (wo)man to get interested in art - it is in our genes, as long as we figure out which specific art form we are interested in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;playing-outdoor-games&quot;&gt;playing outdoor games&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I already talked about indoor games (yet barely. Its a vast field - ranging from board games, puzzles, role playing, etc. and the elephant in the room - video games). We all know the merits of outdoor games - learning to play by the rules, sportsmanship, team spirit, being graceful in defeat, preparing and planning for success etc. For now, let her play the street games with her friends, she still has another 2 or 3 years to go to learn and master a good outdoor game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;self-defence&quot;&gt;self-defence&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This seems to be more and more essential these days, Karate seems to be the preferred weapon of choice (Judo/Boxing/Krav Maga/wrestling are other pop options), I’ll put this under art form/outdoor games and not as a separate category. See if she is interested in learning one of this skill and go from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;other-essentials&quot;&gt;other ‘essentials’&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;swimming&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;riding bicycle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;one or two foreign languages other than Tamil and English. (Hindi of course)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;programming (I know that you can work on your left or right brain and not both, but I’d introduce her to programming sometime around 9-10 years anyway and see how it goes)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cooking (not because she is a girl, but learning to cook the ‘exciting’ stuff such as cakes, desserts, international recipes. I wish I knew more items to cook.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I write this down I make a vow to make sure that I don’t force her to pursue any of these which she is not interested in pursuing. Childhood should be fun, you don’t need to know &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of these or even &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; of these to have an awesome childhood, at the same time I do realize that it is my responsibility to expose her to as many fun opportunities as possible - within my economic and geographical limitations. I’m excited about her future, it is going to be fun.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2015 18:41:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://balaji-damodaran.com/personal/2015/09/06/introducing-money-to-kids.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://balaji-damodaran.com/personal/2015/09/06/introducing-money-to-kids.html</guid>
        
        <category>parenting</category>
        
        <category>money</category>
        
        <category>monopoly</category>
        
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Trip to Tenkasi, Thenmala and back</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/tn-ride.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Route map&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 class=&quot;center&quot; id=&quot;route-map&quot;&gt;Route map&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Besant Nagar –&amp;gt; Madurai –&amp;gt; Tenkasi –&amp;gt; Thenmala –&amp;gt; Marthandam –&amp;gt; Dindugul –&amp;gt; Chennai&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;1547 km. 56 hrs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;highlightsnotes-to-self&quot;&gt;Highlights/Notes to self:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chennai traffic is broken beyond repair.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tambaram to Singaperumal Koil is teeming with life, this region is to Chennai what North east is to India - ‘not worth knowing’. Now its the hotbed of land mafia and US return IT couples.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hotel Balaji bhavan after Mamandoor is of good quality - they give six different sides for Dosas.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Riding on highway is as safe as riding on city.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Madurai rocks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Paruthi paal (cotton seed milk) tastes like payasam.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meenakshi Amman temple has a good museum - 1000 pillared mandapam. Entry ticket is Rs.5, but go in even numbers because they won’t have Rs.5 change.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Idiyappam with paya and kari dosai is a delight.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All roads lead to Madurai.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Since all roads lead to Madurai, it is easy to take the wrong road.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/madurai-konar-kadai.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Idiyappam with aattukkal paya in Simmakkal Konar kadai, Madurai.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 class=&quot;center&quot; id=&quot;idiyappam-with-aattukkal-paya-in-simmakkal-konar-kadai-madurai&quot;&gt;Idiyappam with aattukkal paya in Simmakkal Konar kadai, Madurai.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tenkasi road is so so. Single lane, difficult to overtake and there are enough slow moving vehicles.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Srivilliputhur and Rajapalayam are quite small towns.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is not a good idea for two 6ft tall persons to ride on the same bike.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When you want to buy something on the road, buy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Small villages with its vast fields are very calming.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plan ahead, buy a gift for the wedding.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/tenkasi-wedding.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Senthil - Abinaya wedding.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 class=&quot;center&quot; id=&quot;senthil---abinaya-wedding-tenkasi-any-guesses-why-our-hands-are-tied-behind-the-back-no-gifts&quot;&gt;Senthil - Abinaya wedding, Tenkasi. Any guesses why our hands are tied behind the back? (no gifts)&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sengottai - Thenmala road to Kerala is enchanting, do it again.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kerala twisties are good fun.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;90% of cars I saw in Kerala are Maruti. 90% of those Maruti are Alto variants.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;90% of the bikes I saw in Kerala are Yamaha FZ variants.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In Kerala they play kabaddi-like-football thing on the road, its like waiting for crackers to burst in Deepavali, you need to stop and wait for the person to kick the ball and then go.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/somewhere-after-thenmala.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Somewhere after Thenmala (South mountain, not honey mountain).&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 class=&quot;center&quot; id=&quot;somewhere-after-thenmala-means-southern-mountain-not-honey-mountain&quot;&gt;Somewhere after Thenmala (means Southern mountain, not honey mountain).&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is natural in Kerala to block passengers on road for funds collection.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People protest on the road all of the time, even on the eve of Onam.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kerala twisties are good fun, but once the night sets in, the roads can get a bit scary.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google maps knows the shortest path, even if it is a deserted residential battered narrow haunting road.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If there is a google maps fan club, count me in.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If a caption in a hotel says ‘never tip our waiters, its insulting their service’, expect the waiter to stand next to you until you tip.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Night ride is fun - far less traffic and no scorching sun - provided you have enough mojo to last for the ride.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fast moving cars on night rides mostly come in pairs - this was interesting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/couple.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wife asked me to send the photo of the couple.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 class=&quot;center&quot; id=&quot;wife-asked-me-to-send-the-photo-of-the-couple&quot;&gt;Wife asked me to send the photo of the couple.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are windmills in Tirunelveli and Thootukudi for a reason, it gets extremely windy as they are situated on the foothills of the western ghats. If you are in two wheeler, expect one hell of a ride.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Since all roads lead to Madurai, it is easy to take the wrong road - more so at night and screw up your plans.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Never ask for directions to a drunken old man at 1 AM.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dindugul - Trichy highway is as good as it can be, but expect shockingly battered roads as you reach Trichy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Besant Nagar to Velankanni pilgrims walk at night to cover the distance without sun. For some reason they go via Dindugul.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is better to ride through a city at 4 AM than at 9 AM.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Petrol bunks on highways are night oases, you’ll know its true worth when you have bowel pressure.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Toll booths at night are the best places to find snacks and open bathrooms.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When you ride from 3 PM to 6 AM the next day and doze off on the bike, give up and get some sleep.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Despite our best intentions shit happens. Watch out for a calf to walk into the road from the median and get hit by a car. Thank your stars that it was not you in your bike. (The calf survived, the car was damaged quite badly.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chennai traffic is broken beyond repair.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;regrets&quot;&gt;Regrets:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Didn’t stop in Ponmudi/Colachel/Kanyakumari.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Because I had to be in Chennai on Saturday and that meant that I needed enough rest, staying in Ponmudi or Kanyakumari on Thursday night would’ve left me riding on Friday daytime to reach Chennai by night and immediately travel the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;I was slightly uneasy to spend money in Ponmudi, its a hill station and a stay would’ve been costly.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;I really wanted to do a night ride.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Didn’t experience the presence of gigantic windmills from Nagercoil to Tirunelveli as I was doing a night ride.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Didn’t buy Srivilliputhur paalkova. It is one of the lasting images of my childhood. Dad would buy this when he used to come from work on weekends to our home in Virudhunagar. It used to be a single block of quarter kg sweet. Me and my brother will cut it in the middle and finish it in one sitting! Fun times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2015 02:41:54 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://balaji-damodaran.com/personal/2015/08/29/tamil-nadu-roundtrip.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://balaji-damodaran.com/personal/2015/08/29/tamil-nadu-roundtrip.html</guid>
        
        <category>motorcycling</category>
        
        <category>tenkasi</category>
        
        <category>thenmala</category>
        
        <category>madurai</category>
        
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Trip to Tirumala Hills</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This independence day weekend Arun and I planned to go to Tirumala hills, which is the home of arguably one of the richest temples in the world, the temple of - Sri Venkateswara Swamy or Lord Balaji.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/helmet-selfie.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Helmet selfies&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 class=&quot;center&quot; id=&quot;helmet-selfie&quot;&gt;Helmet Selfie!&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We left by 8 am from Sri Motel highway after breakfast. The climate was hot and dry. Tirumazhisai - Tiruvallur road was not smooth at all. With patched roads that really were just upside down pot holes and we had to cross the Tiruvallur town which didn’t have roads at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/en-route-tirupathi.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;En route to Tirupathi&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 class=&quot;center&quot; id=&quot;en-route-to-tirupathi-after-nagari&quot;&gt;En route to Tirupathi, after Nagari&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we reached the national highway (NH 205), the roads were pretty good. We passed through Tiruttani and Nagari without any event and by mistake went inside Tirupathi town. Arun’s number plate was missing a screw, we stopped for him to search for a hardware shop, the sun was scorching down. Tirupathi town was big with a lot of multi storied apartments. Majority of the cars had TN number plates and quite a good number of them with MH number plates as well. After asking for directions within the city’s police and auto dirvers (this required us to negotiate some crazy traffic), we managed to reach the toll that takes you to the top of the hill which is around 20km from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/tirupathi-toll.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tirupathi tollbooth view&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 class=&quot;center&quot; id=&quot;tirupathi-tollbooth-view&quot;&gt;Tirupathi tollbooth view&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was security check and there are certain restrictions on what you can and cannot carry to the top, for e.g. liquor, camera etc. are banned. It was independence day as well, so I was expecting some strict checks. The security guard was amused by my armored jacket and he wanted to know why it was too hard - may be he thought I was carrying explosives or something fishy. I had to remove by jacket and show him that it was just a plastic material. The toll was 2 Rupees for bikes - thank Lord Balaji that I retained the 2 rupees from the breakfast bill and did not give it away with the tip, otherwise I had only 100 and 500 rupee notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/google-maps-route.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Google maps route&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 class=&quot;center&quot; id=&quot;google-maps-route&quot;&gt;Google maps route&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best thing about riding to Tirumala is that - the road uphill and downhill are one-ways. They are two different routes. So it is very safe to drive uphill and overtake slow moving vehicles. I didn’t drive that fast anyways, but I thoroughly enjoyed the ride. One blogger said that this is the Nurburgring of India, but that will be an exaggeration and a false statement. The road downhill was much more steeper with a lot more U bends and a lot more traffic - I didn’t really enjoy driving down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Tirumala, we walked around the devastham’s cottages - they are very good for the price they offer, but always booked full. People come with all sorts of recommendation letters - from government officials, politicans, TTD employees, etc., just to get into one of these cottages. We thought of having lunch there itself and managed to get into one of the worst ‘canteens’ - this was a bad decision. We asked for poori, after 15 minutes or so, the waiter says that poori is old and not good to eat. We should’ve left the hotel by then, but I made the mistake of asking for dosa, which we did get, but… lets just say that the food ingestion was a regrettable affair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/tirumala-cottages.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tirumala cottages&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 class=&quot;center&quot; id=&quot;tirumala-cottages&quot;&gt;Tirumala cottages&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We left Tirumala by 12.30-ish and reached home by 4 pm. Stopping once or twice on the way for hydrating ourselves. Overall it was a good experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 06:41:54 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://balaji-damodaran.com/personal/2015/08/15/tirumala-trip.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://balaji-damodaran.com/personal/2015/08/15/tirumala-trip.html</guid>
        
        <category>motorcycling</category>
        
        <category>tirumala</category>
        
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Motorcycling as a hobby</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;TL:DR; Personal post. Nothing worth reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was late to motorcycling, but as a kid I used to love cycling. It felt like I was flying. I didn’t own a cycle until I was 10 or 11. But those days, we can rent a cycle for 1 hour for 1 rupee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first rode a motorized vehicle, it was an old Bajaj vespa scooter and I was 16. The next year my brother bought a pulsar and the next year I bought a used Royal Enfield Bullet Standard 350. I loved the riding comfort, the beat and the style mainly. This started my tryst with motorcycling. My college was close to 16km away from my house and my house was 25km away from the city. So, I’m used to being in the bike more often than not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I got a job and now my offices were either 30km south or 20km north. So the riding continued.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I got married and had a kid and then I had another kid. So my priorities were different. I sold my bullet, with a heavy heart I must add. I remember the day when the new owner came to collect the bullet and I never left my bedroom. I bought a commuter bike for married life - Hero Honda Hunk. Now that my life has settled into a rythm (more or less), my heart started to wander a bit. Call it midlife crisis, call it ‘answering my inner voice’ or just reawakening of my desire to ride - I bought a Royal Enfield Bullet Standard 500 (this one is with the new UCE engine, that is way better sans the charm of the old CI engine) and I joined a local motorcycling club with an intention to ride often and ride long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its been 4 months since I bought my &lt;del&gt;bike&lt;/del&gt; bullet. I’ve already been to a places like Javadi hills, Yelagiri hills, Pondicherry, Mysore, Mahabalipuram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;so-here-are-some-note-to-self-when-it-comes-to-riding&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, here are some &lt;em&gt;Note to Self&lt;/em&gt; when it comes to riding.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;# Skills&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like any other hobby - you need skill to drive the machine. To ensure that you control the bike and not the other way, to save yourself and others on the road. This is a costly hobby - right from the bike to riding gear to petrol to tools to travel expenses. You can’t pirate or borrow (atleast not everything). My initial learning was done the hard way - I made &lt;strong&gt;every&lt;/strong&gt; mistake there is to make while riding a motorcycle - and luckily I survived and the knowledge of surviving an accident helps in anticipating another accident that will be similar to the one you had, but this will not equip you to handle another type of accident to which you are not prepared for. I’m relying on by peers’ knowledge as well as some excellent riding manuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;maintenance&quot;&gt;Maintenance&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Invest in the tools. If you love program development - then buy the best computer and ergonomic equipments - keyword, mouse, table, chair, etc. Similarly, when it comes to riding - invest in the best motorcyle that would suit your personality, suit your riding posture and suit your intentions. Learn the art of maintaining the bike, take it part and put it back together. It is a harsh reality for every bullet owner and generally a good advise for every bike owner. oh BTW, fixing a bike in itself is an art form that may people pursue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-it-means-to-ride&quot;&gt;What it means to ride&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its kind of an silly question actually. Its like asking a person ‘what it is to read a book or listen to a song or watch a movie or sew a dress’. The answer is the same. It makes me happy. It puts me in a zone that is close to meditation, in a mood that makes me feel like I’m flying without cluttered emotions. It puts me in touch with mother earth in all her glory. As a rider pointed out in his blog &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hoohoohoblin.com/&quot;&gt;http://www.hoohoohoblin.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Riding a motorcycle is a form of karma yoga.  Karma literally translated means “action.”  Many people have misinterpreted it as the law of cause and effect, but that is not accurate.  Though it is true that if you are truly connected to everything, and everything is connected to you, then that which you do to another person, you are also doing to yourself, because you are that, they are that, and that is all there is.  But this doesn’t mean you will be punished for doing bad things to other people, or that someone is keeping score and will even things up before you die.  Riding a motorcycle is a way to clear the mind, interact with physical reality, and feel connected to the world.  I like it.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and thats all there is to it. I will ride as long as it is possible for me to.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 04:32:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://balaji-damodaran.com/personal/2015/08/11/motorcycling.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://balaji-damodaran.com/personal/2015/08/11/motorcycling.html</guid>
        
        <category>motorcycling</category>
        
        <category>hobbies</category>
        
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>AWS Elastic Beanstalk, Docker and Nginx</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS Elastic Beanstalk is the equivalent of ‘rails’[1] in AWS world to deploy a project (almost in any stack) as quickly as possible without handling the low level details such as web servers, reverse proxies, load balancers, security groups, auto scaling groups, etc. So when you intend to host a cluster of nginx reverse proxies, AWS Elastic Beanstalk seems to a good choice, but unfortunately there aren’t much literature out there on how to do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;docker&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we need to treat nginx as an application deployed on a cluster of machines managed by a load balancer, may be within VPC and auto scaling rules. Docker is a good option in such a case because it makes no assumptions about the kind of application that will be deployed on top of it and AWS Elastic Beanstalk has first class support for dockers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;single-container-docker-vs-multi-container-docker&quot;&gt;Single container Docker vs Multi-container Docker&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AWS Elastic Beanstalk supports both single container and multi container dockers. The difference being that: single container docker uses the first port in the &lt;code&gt;EXPOSE&lt;/code&gt; directive in docker file and maps it to port 80 and it will ingore any other ports. Multi container docker has provision to expose multiple ports out of a docker image and also map them to multiple load balancers (needs scripting). In this blog post, I’ll be talking only about &lt;em&gt;Single container&lt;/em&gt; docker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;step-1---dockerfile--dockerrunawsjson&quot;&gt;Step 1 - Dockerfile &amp;amp; Dockerrun.aws.json&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;FROM ubuntu:trusty
RUN apt-get update
RUN apt-get install -y nginx nginx-extras

RUN rm -vf /etc/nginx/nginx.conf

COPY nginx.conf /etc/nginx/
RUN echo &quot;daemon off;&quot; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; /etc/nginx/nginx.conf

EXPOSE 80

CMD [&quot;service&quot;, &quot;nginx&quot; &quot;start&quot;]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above &lt;code&gt;Dockerfile&lt;/code&gt; is self-explanatory. It downloads the ubuntu trusty image, installs nginx and nginx-extras.
Copies our customized &lt;code&gt;nginx.conf&lt;/code&gt; file and starts the nginx server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;step-2---dockerrunawsjson-file&quot;&gt;Step 2 - Dockerrun.aws.json file&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AWS Elastic Beanstalk requires a Dockerrun.aws.json file for deployment of docker containers. There are two formats. One for single container and other for multi container docker environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
  &quot;AWSEBDockerrunVersion&quot;: &quot;1&quot;,
  &quot;Volumes&quot;: []
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above code is the most basic file that you need for docker deployment. More detailed options are in AWS docmentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;step-3---done&quot;&gt;Step 3 - Done&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thats all you need to deploy a ‘nginx application’ to AWS Elastic Beanstalk with all this goodness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most deployment scenarios will not be this simple and we would have to handle environment specific constraints such as server names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;step-4---environment-specific-configuration&quot;&gt;Step 4 - Environment specific configuration&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typically in a AWS Elastic Beanstalk environment environment specific configuration are handled in the &lt;code&gt;configurations&lt;/code&gt; tab and they would be available to the application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Say for example, if we have test and production specific services and want two different nginx environments to handle them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A typical Dockerfile configuraiton would become:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;FROM ubuntu:trusty

RUN apt-get update
RUN apt-get install -y nginx nginx-extras

RUN rm -vf /etc/nginx/nginx.conf
RUN rm -vf /etc/nginx/conf.d/upstream-services-${API_ENVIRONMENT}.conf

COPY nginx.conf /etc/nginx/
COPY upstream-services-${API_ENVIRONMENT}.conf /etc/nginx/conf.d/
RUN echo &quot;daemon off;&quot; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; /etc/nginx/nginx.conf

EXPOSE 8081

CMD [&quot;/usr/bin/supervisord&quot;]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;where &lt;code&gt;API_ENVIRONMENT&lt;/code&gt; is defined in Elastic Beanstalk. We will have &lt;code&gt;upsteram-services-test.conf&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;upstream-services-production.conf&lt;/code&gt; in source to handle environment specific upstream servers while keeping the common rules in &lt;code&gt;nginx.conf&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;e.g. upstream-services-test.conf&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;upstream test {
  server invoice-test.example.com;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;upstream-services-production.conf&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;upstream test {
  server invoice-prod.example.com;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this is being a pre-built docker image, those environment configurations will not be available to docker at &lt;em&gt;build&lt;/em&gt; time. Most probably you need those configuration settings at &lt;em&gt;build&lt;/em&gt; time. So, here’s a nice script that can read AWS Elastic Beanstalk environment configuration and write it do Dockerfile before building the docker image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what we need is a way to edit dockerfile to pass environment variables &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; it gets built into an container image.
The below code snippet is an &lt;code&gt;.ebextensions&lt;/code&gt; config file for AWS Elastic Beanstalk that creates a script file and executes it during the docker build process. Most of the code for this script is from this stackoveflow answer: &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/a/30359445&quot;&gt;http://stackoverflow.com/a/30359445&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;files:
  &quot;/opt/elasticbeanstalk/hooks/appdeploy/pre/02export_env_vars_on_host.sh&quot;:
    mode: &quot;000755&quot;
    owner: root
    group: root
    content: |
      #!/usr/bin/env bash
      echo Defaults:root \!requiretty &amp;gt;&amp;gt; /etc/sudoers
      for envvar in `jq &#39;.optionsettings | {&quot;aws:elasticbeanstalk:application:environment&quot;}[] | .[]&#39; /opt/elasticbeanstalk/deploy/configuration/containerconfiguration`
      do
        temp=&quot;${envvar//\&quot;/}&quot;;
        temp=&quot;${temp/=/ }&quot;;
        sed -i &quot;/FROM ubuntu:trusty/a ENV $temp&quot; /var/app/current/Dockerfile
      done
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above code snippet, reads environment specific variables from AWS Elastic Beanstalk and inserts them as &lt;code&gt;ENV&lt;/code&gt; directives to &lt;code&gt;Dockerfile&lt;/code&gt; before it gets built. This is important and as of writing &lt;code&gt;appdeploy/pre/02&lt;/code&gt; is a safe position as &lt;code&gt;01&lt;/code&gt; step is unzip of source code and &lt;code&gt;03&lt;/code&gt; step is the actual build process of docker container.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;step-5-running-multiple-processes&quot;&gt;Step 5: Running multiple processes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Docker images should be treated as ‘processes’ and a single container should ideally run only on process.
But almost in all cases, we would need more than one process to run, say for example - monitoring. In such cases, it would be better to use a process control system such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://supervisord.org/&quot;&gt;supervisord&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2015 04:32:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://balaji-damodaran.com/programming/2015/08/09/elastic-beanstalk-docker.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://balaji-damodaran.com/programming/2015/08/09/elastic-beanstalk-docker.html</guid>
        
        <category>docker</category>
        
        <category>nginx</category>
        
        <category>AWS</category>
        
        <category>Elastic Beanstalk</category>
        
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nginx CORS headers, proxy_pass and if module</title>
        <description>&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Setting up reverse proxy in nginx is straight forward using the proxy_pass directive.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;location /reversed-proxy {
  proxy_pass http://example.com;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Adding CORS headers on proxy_pass. More information about HTTP access control here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/Access_control_CORS&quot;&gt;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/Access_control_CORS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; location /reversed-proxy {
   proxy_pass http://example.com;
   add_header &#39;Access-Control-Allow-Origin&#39; &#39;*&#39;;
   add_header &#39;Access-Control-Allow-Methods&#39; &#39;POST,GET,OPTIONS&#39;;
 }
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The above example allows cross-domain requests from all websites. The right way to restrict them is to use regex match on the origin:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; location /reversed-proxy {
   proxy_pass http://example.com;
   if ($http_origin ~* &#39;https?://(www\.foobar\.com)&#39;) {
     add_header &#39;Access-Control-Allow-Origin&#39; &quot;$http_origin&quot;;
   }
   add_header &#39;Access-Control-Allow-Methods&#39; &#39;POST,GET,OPTIONS&#39;;
 }
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You may also want to ensure that preflight requests from browsers are handled properly. Please read the mozilla link above to find out what is a preflight request and in what condition is it sent to the server.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; location /reversed-proxy {
   proxy_pass http://example.com;
   if ($http_origin ~* &#39;https?://(www\.foobar\.com)&#39;) {
     add_header &#39;Access-Control-Allow-Origin&#39; &quot;$http_origin&quot;;
   }

   #preflight request
   if ($request_method = &#39;OPTIONS&#39;) {
     add_header &#39;Access-Control-Max-Age&#39; &#39;1728000&#39;;
     add_header &#39;Content-Type&#39; &#39;text/plain charset=UTF-8&#39;;
     add_header &#39;Content-Length&#39; &#39;0&#39;;
     return 204;
   }
   add_header &#39;Access-Control-Allow-Methods&#39; &#39;POST,GET,OPTIONS&#39;;
 }
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;The snippet 3) and 4) may look harmless to a person with imperative langauges background such as java, javascript, but it is completely broken!&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;For e.g. In case of preflight request, the response headers will not have the &lt;code&gt;&#39;Access-control-allow-origin&#39;&lt;/code&gt; header. Because,
 Nginx declaratively finds the right &lt;code&gt;if&lt;/code&gt; block to execute, in preflight request’s case it will be the second &lt;code&gt;if&lt;/code&gt; block and it executes only its contents imperatively.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;There is also another quirk, if its a GET request originating from foobar.com, nginx will match it with the first if block - declaratively and request to proxy_pass will be sent as &lt;code&gt;example.com/reversed-proxy/$1&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;example.com/$1&lt;/code&gt;, because the if block acts as a nested location block and &lt;code&gt;/reversed&lt;/code&gt; is treated as url path.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Such errors have been documented extensively - &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.nginx.org/IfIsEvil&quot;&gt;http://wiki.nginx.org/IfIsEvil&lt;/a&gt; Hence, examples such as these &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/alexjs/4165271&quot;&gt;https://gist.github.com/alexjs/4165271&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/michiel/1064640&quot;&gt;https://gist.github.com/michiel/1064640&lt;/a&gt; don’t seem to work in the context of proxy_pass because of the issue with if block.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If we want restrictive CORS accesss + reverse proxy + nginx then we cannot use &lt;code&gt;if&lt;/code&gt; block at all. The best alternative is to use &lt;code&gt;map&lt;/code&gt; module. More information here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://nginx.org/en/docs/http/ngx_http_map_module.html&quot;&gt;http://nginx.org/en/docs/http/ngx_http_map_module.html&lt;/a&gt;. It works like a pattern matching block and fits perfectly well in CORS scenario.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;The solution is given in stackoverflow: &lt;a href=&quot;https://serverfault.com/questions/674900/nginx-if-statement-inside-location-returns-404/674901#674901&quot;&gt;https://serverfault.com/questions/674900/nginx-if-statement-inside-location-returns-404/674901#674901&lt;/a&gt;, documenting in the blog for completeness. To solve the broken snippet above, we should do this:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; map $http_host $cors_header {
   hostnames;
   default &quot;&quot;;
   .foobar.com &quot;$http_origin&quot;;
 }

 server {
   location /reversed-proxy {
     proxy_pass http://example.com;
     add_header &#39;Access-Control-Allow-Origin&#39; $cors_header;
     add_header &#39;Access-Control-Allow-Methods&#39; &#39;POST,GET,OPTIONS&#39;;

     #preflight request
     if ($request_method = &#39;OPTIONS&#39;) {
       add_header &#39;Access-Control-Max-Age&#39; &#39;1728000&#39;;
       add_header &#39;Content-Type&#39; &#39;text/plain charset=UTF-8&#39;;
       add_header &#39;Content-Length&#39; &#39;0&#39;;

       add_header &#39;Access-Control-Allow-Origin&#39; $cors_header;
       add_header &#39;Access-Control-Allow-Methods&#39; &#39;POST,GET,OPTIONS&#39;;
       return 204;
     }
   }
 }
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;notice the two access control headers duplicated inside and outside the &lt;code&gt;if&lt;/code&gt; block, its not a mistake. Its because nginx finds the &lt;code&gt;if&lt;/code&gt; block to execute declaratively and skips the code outside the block.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Thats all.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 06:41:54 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://balaji-damodaran.com/programming/2015/07/30/nginx-headers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://balaji-damodaran.com/programming/2015/07/30/nginx-headers.html</guid>
        
        <category>nginx</category>
        
        <category>cors</category>
        
        <category>reverse proxy</category>
        
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Capistrano &amp; Java (or using capistrano to execute remote commands)</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;assumption&quot;&gt;Assumption:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capistrano for java works if the deployment involves doing a git checkout on a server machine and building the package - a command similar to &lt;code&gt;mvn clean package&lt;/code&gt;. If there are proper deployment structures in place such as a CI server, or you do not/can not build your war file in the server machine - then it doesn’t really help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;prerequisites&quot;&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to have ruby installed in local machine, install capistano gem and have run &lt;code&gt;cap install&lt;/code&gt; anywhere -it doesn’t really matter if the files are in the root directory of the project or in a separate directly. But it is better to have the capistrano files along with the source code. More install instructions in the capistrano website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to&quot;&gt;How To:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://capistranorb.com&quot;&gt;Capistrano&lt;/a&gt; essentially executes commands remotely on a machine. So, we can ‘in principle’ use capistrano to do any arbitrary jobs that involves remote execution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To achieve that we need to override any ruby specific tasks that gets executed by capistrano.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;bundle install&lt;/code&gt; task gets executed on &lt;code&gt;deploy:finalize_update&lt;/code&gt;, so this needs to be overridden.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;deploy:restart&lt;/code&gt; task touches &lt;code&gt;tmp/restart.txt&lt;/code&gt; - doesn’t make sense in Java world.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The whole &lt;code&gt;deploy:finalize_update&lt;/code&gt; step is not necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, in our &lt;code&gt;Capfile&lt;/code&gt;, we override these tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;namespace :deploy do
# override ruby specific tasks
	task :finalize_update do; end
	task :restart do; end
  	end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

  	namespace :bundle do
  	#override bundle install task
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;	task :install do; end
 	end

# create the task which will needs to be executed in remote machine. such as mvn deploy
  	namespace :tomcat do
	task :deploy do
  	run &quot;cd #{deploy_to}/current; mvn clean tomcat7:redeploy&quot;
	end
  	end

#invoke the task after the &#39;create_symlink&#39; stage in capistrano
after &#39;deploy:create_symlink&#39;, &#39;tomcat:deploy&#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;      	run &quot;cd #{deploy_to}/current; mvn clean tomcat7:redeploy&quot;&lt;/code&gt; is where interesting part is. You should already have this code &lt;code&gt;set :deploy_to /path/to/deploy&lt;/code&gt; in the cap file.
Instead of this command, we can &lt;code&gt;run&lt;/code&gt; almost any command and have it executed in the remote machine, thus reusing capistrano for any other application.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://balaji-damodaran.com/programming/2014/04/27/capistrano-for-deploying-java.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://balaji-damodaran.com/programming/2014/04/27/capistrano-for-deploying-java.html</guid>
        
        <category>capistrano</category>
        
        <category>java</category>
        
        <category>deployment</category>
        
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello World</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Customary hello world page. I’m typing this in vim on Mac OS X 10.9.
Vim has been a revelation for me. My current vim setup is here &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/balaji/config_files/blob/master/vim/.vimrc&quot;&gt;https://github.com/balaji/config_files/blob/master/vim/.vimrc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I’m struggling without mouse to do anything related with multiple files like navigation, search and editing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vim configuration uses &lt;code&gt;Vundle&lt;/code&gt;. Loving the ease of installing a plugin which used to be for me a very tedious process. Even &lt;code&gt;pathogen&lt;/code&gt; is a good alternative. Just that &lt;code&gt;Vundle&lt;/code&gt; eliminates the last bit of manual effort compared to &lt;code&gt;pathogen&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2014 06:41:54 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://balaji-damodaran.com/personal/2014/04/21/hello-world.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://balaji-damodaran.com/personal/2014/04/21/hello-world.html</guid>
        
        <category>vim</category>
        
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
